Contact

bhupendra.singh.che19@iitbh u.ac.in

www.linkedin.com/in/bhupendrasingh-iitbhu (LinkedIn) bhupendra-singhportfolio.netlify.app/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Problem Solving

Angular

Python (Programming Language)

Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

Honors-Awards

Tata Steel - Mat E Reality 2021 Hacktoberfest 2021 badge

Publications

Advanced Next.js Concepts
Build a Blog Website with Next.js

Bhupendra Singh

Software Engineer @Carelon || Ex-SDE @Dexterio || IIT BHU'23 || Techstacks (MERN, MEAN, Django, Python)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

Summary

Hey there,

I am a software engineer, specializing in full-stack development. For the last few years, I have been developing web applications using MERN, MEAN, Next.js, Django, and Python programming languages.

Currently, I am working as a software engineer at Carelon Global Solutions, formerly known as Legato. I'm skilled to work across all the stages of software development cycles,. from planning and design to testing and deployment. I've also worked at Dexterio Pvt. Ltd. previously. There, I was leading the development of 2 platforms for creating a marketplace for interior and exterior designers to connect with clients and vice versa.

Something that I really love about being in the tech industry is that you get the opportunity to optimize solutions for efficient resource distribution and utilization. This helps you solve the problems in the best possible way, not just while working professionally but personally as well. And for someone who loves to connect with people, it's a great opportunity to have connections with so many different people and departments.

I always love to connect with techies. If you are interested in collaborating, discussing potential opportunities, or exchanging ideas, please connect with me on LinkedIn or reach out via email.

Skills: C++, Data Structures & Algorithms, MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js), Next.js, Redux.js, Python, Django, GraphQL & Restful API's development.

Experience

Carelon Global Solutions Software Engineer July 2023 - Present (9 months)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

Dexterio Software Development Engineer March 2022 - August 2022 (6 months) Remote

Software Development Engineer:

➤ Led the development of an end-to-end solution for interior and exterior designers, enabling seamless fulfillment of client demands, including raw materials and tools. Built the front-end using Next.js and Tailwind CSS, providing designers with a user-friendly interface to create designs, projects, and portfolios.

Client-Side Services and Utility Development:

> Contributed to the development of client-side services, including dashboards, project management tools, and landing pages. Leveraged technologies such as Next.js, Tailwind CSS, React-PDF, Apollo Client, MongoDB, and AWS S3 to build robust and scalable utilities to enhance the user experience.

GraphQL Integration and Server-Side Rendering:

> Managed data integration through 28 mutations and 17 queries using GraphQL and Apollo Client. Implemented server-side rendering across protected and public routes, ensuring efficient performance and secure data communication for the application.

Ranckin Web Developer May 2021 - June 2021 (2 months) Remote

Frontend Developer:

> Designed and developed frontend using React.js for Ranckin's platform, connecting JEE, AIIMS, NEET medical aspirants with mentors. Implemented authentication with Google, Facebook, and customized login/signup functions.

API Implementation:

➤ Developed APIs for seamless communication between the server and database, ensuring efficient data retrieval and management. Utilized JavaScript, MongoDB, and GitHub for reliable backend functionality.

Kashiyatra, IIT (BHU) Varanasi Public Relations Coordinator January 2020 - March 2020 (3 months) Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India

Education

Indian Institute of Technology (Banaras Hindu University), Varanasi B.Tech · (2019 - 2023)

S. S. Public School, Agra 12th · (2018 - 2019)

S. S. Public School, Agra 10th · (2016 - 2017)